Roland Lamb Papers MS136
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Roland Lamb Papers
1888 -- 1896
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Lamb, Roland
MS136
1.2 Linear Feet 1 box, 3 oversize folders
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series. Materials are arranged alphabetically within each box or map case.
Biographical / Historical
Roland M. Lamb (1878-1935) was born in Massachusetts in October 1878 to Louis J. Lamb and Elizabeth B. Lamb. After attending Attleboro High School, he matriculated at Tufts College in the fall of 1896, together with his brother Arthur. During his time at Tufts, Lamb was admitted as a member to the Delta Upsilon fraternity, and was the manager of the Tufts football team during its 1899 fall season. After graduating in 1900 with a Bachelor of Arts, Lamb worked as a real estate broker; he later worked as a superintendent in the dredging industry. He married Elnora P. Lamb in 1909. Lamb died December 30, 1935.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains papers of Roland Lamb. Materials include correspondence and his participation in the Delta Upsilon Fraternity. There are also a number of photos documenting the fraternity, Tufts' football manager, and speeches given by professors. One oversized folder also contains poster-sized political drawings.
Alumni collections; College fraternity members; Alumni and alumnae; Student life; Lamb, Roland
- Ronald Lamb Papers, 1888 -- 1896; MS136.001
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  General
  - Attleboro High School events, circa 1895 -- 1900; MS136.001.001.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Classmate photos, circa 1895 -- 1900; MS136.001.001.00002; 4 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Congressional speeches, circa 1893 -- 1896; MS136.001.001.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Delta Upsilon Fraternity, Tufts University, circa 1896 -- 1900; MS136.001.001.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Lamb's athletic activities, Tufts football manager, circa 1898 -- 1899; MS136.001.001.00005; 5 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Lamb's bike business: correspondence and receipts, circa 1894 -- 1896; MS136.001.001.00006; 3 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Lamb's college essays, circa 1896 -- 1900; MS136.001.001.00007; 4 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Music sheets: campus song and class song, circa 1896 -- 1900; MS136.001.001.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Personal correspondence, poem, dance cards, circa 1895 -- 1901; MS136.001.001.00009; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Shredded letterhead: Lamb's correspondence, circa 1899; MS136.001.001.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Tufts events: professor speech, banquets, circa 1895 -- 1901; MS136.001.001.00011; 7 Folder(s) (Box 1)
  - Delta Upsilon Fraternity, circa 1896 -- 1900; MS136.001.002.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box Small Map Case 1 Drawer 4, Folder data_value_missing_346889c7626fa4717a1ba342935d45ea)
  - Delta Upsilon Fraternity, circa 1896 -- 1900; MS136.001.002.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box Small Map Case 1 Drawer 4)
  - The New York Tribune posters, numbers 1-4, 1888 -- 1896; MS136.001.002.00001 (Box Small Map Case 1 Drawer 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Posters in color.
    poster